Finding Aid for the Avery Leiserson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Writings by others – book reviews
  - Ryan, Alan “The Politics of Dignity” review of The Decent Society by Avishai Margalit in The New York Review of Books, July 11, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Ryan, Alan “Who Was Edmund Burke?” review of The Great Melody: a Thematic Biography and Commented Anthology of Edmund Burke by Conor Cruise O’Brien in The New York Review of Books, Dec. 3, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Book reviews “Empirical Theory and Methodology” in American Political Science Review, Vol. 77, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Salisbury, R.F.”Models for a United Social Science” review of The Logic of Social Systems by Alfred Kuhn in Science, Vol. 187, January 1975 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Sayle, Murray “KE007: A Conspiracy of Circumstances” review of Black Box: KAL 007 and the Superpowers by Alexander Dallin; KAL Flight 007: The Hidden Story by Oliver Clubb; Final Report of Investigation as Required in the Council Resolution of September 16, 1983 [C-WP/7809], International Civil Aviation Organization; 1818th Report to Council by the President of the Air Navigation Commission [C-WP/7809] International Civil Aviation Organization; North Atlantic Airspace Operations Manual – Fourth Edition, Civil Aviation Authority; NOPAC Route Systems Operations Handbook, Anchorage Air Route Traffic Control Center, Federal Aviation Administration in The New York Review of Books, April 25, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Scully, Michael “Capitalism’s ‘Moral Hazard’” review of Wealth and Poverty by George Gilder in The Public Interest (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Searle, John “The Storm Over the University” review of Tenured Radicals: How Politics Has Corrupted Our Higher Education by Roger Kimball; The Politics of Liberal Education edited by Darrly L. Gless and Barbara Herrnstein Smith; The Voice of Liberal Learning:Michael Oakeshott on Education edited by Timothy Fuller in The New York Review of Books, December 6, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Smith, John Maynard “Natural Selection of Culture?” review of Culture and the Evolutionary Process by Robert Boyd and Peter J. Richerson in The New York Review of Books, Nov. 6, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Solow, Robert M. “Arthur Okun’s Last Work” review of Prices and Quantities: A Macroeconomic Analysis by Arthur M. Okun in The Public Interest (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Solow, Robert M. “On Golden Pond” review of Gray Dawn: How the Coming Age Wave Will Transform America – and the World by Peter G. Peterson in The New York Review of Books, May 6, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Stade, George review of Dimentions of a New Identity by Erik H. Erikson; Civilized Man’s Eight Deadly Sins by Konrad Lorenz in The New York Times Book Review (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Steel, Ronald “Shultz’s Revenge” review of Turmoil and Triumph: My Years as Secretary of State by George P. Shultz in The New York Review of Books, March 26, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Stone, Robert “American Apostle” review of God and the American Writer by Alfred Kazin in The New York Review of Books, March 26, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Thompson, Leonard “Comparatively Speaking” review of The Comparative Imagination: On the History of Racism, Nationalism, and Social Movements by George M. Fredrickson; Black Liberation: A Comparitive History of Black Ideologies in the United States and South Africa by George M. Fredrickson; Comrades in Business: Post-Liberation Politics in South Africa by Heribert Adam, Frederik Van Zyl Slabbert, and Kogila Moodley in The New York Review of Books, May 14, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Tobin, James “How to Think about the Deficit” review of How Real is the Federal Deficit? by Robert Eisner; The Deficits: How Big? How Long? How Dangerous? by Daniel Bell and Lester Thurow, Joseph I. Lubin Memorial Lectures No. 2 in The New York Review of Books, Sept. 25, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Walzer, Michael “The New Masters” review of The Intellectuals on the Road to Class Power by George Konrad and Ivan Szelenyi, trans. by Andrew Arato and Richard E. Allen; The Future of Intellectuals and the Rise of the New Class by Alvin W. Gouldner in The New York Review of Books, March 20, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Wolfe, Alan “What the New Immigrants Can Learn From the Old: The Return of the Melting Pot” review of Ethnic Identity: The Transformation of White America by Richard D.Alba; The American Kaleidoscope: Race, Ethnicity, and the Civic Culture by Lawrence H. Fuchs; Immigrant America: A Portrait by Alejandro Portes and Ruben G.Rumbaut; Ethnic Options: Choosing Identities in America by Mary C. Waters in the New Republic, Dec. 31, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Wood, Gordon S. “ Politics without Party” review of Presidents Above Party: The First American Presidency, 1789 - 1829 by Ralph Ketcham in The New York Review of Books, Oct. 11, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Wood, Gordon S. “Rambunctious American Democracy” review of How Democratic Is the American Constitution? by Robert A. Dahl; On Two Wings: Humble Faith and Common Sense at the American Founding by Michael Novak; James Madison by Garry Wills in The New York Review of Books, May 9, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Wood, Gordon S. “History Lessons” review of The March of Folly: from Troy to Vietnam by Barbara W. Tuchman in The New York Review of Books, March 29, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Wood, Gordon S. “Liberty’s Wild Man” review of The Long Affair: Thomas Jefferson and the French Revolution, 1785 - 1800 by Conor Cruise O’Brien in The New York Review of Books, Feb. 20, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Woodward, C. Vann “The Return of LBJ” review of Lone Star Rising: Lyndon Johnson and His Times, 1908 – 1960 by Robert Dallek; The Triumph and Tragedy of Lyndon Johnson: the White House Years by Joseph A. Califano, Jr. in The New York Review of Books, Dec. 5, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Zald, Mayer N. “Explaining Our Fears” review of Risk and Culture. An Essay on the Selection of Technical and Environmental Dangers by Mary Douglas and Aaron Wildavsky in Science, Vol. 219, March 11, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Writings by others – magazine and newspaper articles
  - Beck, William “The Riddle of Life” in The Saturday Evening Post, May 10, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Berenson, Robert A. “The Single-Payer Trap” in Health Care, Second Opinions, An Occasional Series (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Bethe, Hans A. “The Inferiority Complex” testimony to the Senate Foreign Relations Committee on May 13, 1982 in The New York Review of Books, June 10, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Blumenthal, Sidney “Drafting a Democratic Industrial Plan” in The New York Times Magazine, August 28, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Bouvy, Larry J. “Knowledge of tax law unknown to lawmakers” letter to the Editor in The Tennessean (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Broad, William J. “ Australians Create a Deadly Mouse Virus,”, January 23, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Broder, David “ The Political Parties” in Political Profiles, Inc., 1979 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Broder, David “The Politics of Divided Government: If it’s here to stay, is that cause for alarm?” in The Washington Post National Weekly Edition, September 11 – 17, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Broder, David “Poli – Sci Earthquake” in The Washington Post, June 15, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Broder, David S. “Take Back the Initiative: Special Interests have corrupted our democracy at the grass roots” in The Washington Post National Weekly Edition, April 10, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Chavez, Tim “Readers ask, What’s happened to me? I ask, What’s happened to Democrats?” in The Tennessean (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Clymer, Adam “ PAC Money’s Role in Congress Raises Suspicions” in The New York Times (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Cohen, Stephen F. “Why Bukharin’s Ghost Still Haunts Moscow” in The New York Times Magazine, Dec. 10, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Coughlin, Ellen K. “ Many Political Scientists are Unhappy about Their Jobs, Salaries, Students” in The Chronicle of Higher Education, Sept. 11, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Crittenden, Ann “The ‘Veto Power’ of Big Business” in The New York Times, Jan. 29, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Daughtrey, Larry “Carter Criticizes Moral Majority Saying Its Political Role is Error” in The Tennessean, October 30, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Dale, Edwin L., Jr. “Economic Planners Find 1970 Humbling Experience” in The New York Times, January 24, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Davis, W. Stanley “The Firebug Confesses” in Chess Life, December 1980 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Diggins, John Patrick “The New Republic and Its Times” in The New Republic, December 10, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Draper, Theodore “ ‘How Not to Think About Nuclear War’: An Exchange” in The New York Review of Books, Sept. 23, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Dyson, Freeman “Can Science Be Ethical?” in The New York Review of Books, April 10, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Writings by others - magazine and newspaper articles
  - Fallows, James “America’s Changing Economic Landscape” in The Atlantic Monthly, March 1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Frankel, Charles “ The Nature and Sources of Irrationalism” in Science, Vol. 180, June 1, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Gellman, Barton “The Events That Led to the Confrontation in Kosovo” in The Washington Post National Weekly Edition, March 29, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Gellner, Ernest “Hegel’s Last Secrets: From Marx to Expressivism in Men and Ideas (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Goodman, Walter “When Clashing Political Ideas Really Stirred Passions” in The New York Times, March 25, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Graham, Hugh Davis “Vanderbilt community speaks out on Clinton” in Vanderbilt Register, Sept. 21 – 27, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Halloran, Richard “ Pentagon Draws Up First Strategy For Fighting a Long Nuclear War” in The New York Times, May 30, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Heilbroner, Robert “ Seize the Day” in The New York Review of Books, February 15, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Heilbroner, Robert “ Lifting the Silent Depression” in The New York Review of Books, October 24, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Kemble, Penn “ The Democrats and Their Rules” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Kennedy, Paul “The American Prospect” in The New York Review of Books, March 4, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - King, Wayne “Carter Redux” in The New York Times Magazine, December 10, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Kline, William “ Ashcroft’s views reflect those of nation” letter to the editor in The Tennessean (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Klinkenborg, Verlyn “Hearing the Echo of Earthly Music: Science Again Discovers How Much We Resemble the Rest of Creation” (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Knox, Bernard “The Freedom of Oedipus” in The New Republic, August 30, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Kuttner, Robert “The Poverty of Economics” in The Atlantic Monthly, February 1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. “ The Unmaking of the Republican Party” in Fortune, September 1977 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Ladd, Everett Carll, Jr. “The Life of 2 Parties” (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Lekachman, Robert “ Training a Pleasant Demon” in Saturday Review, March 6, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Lenkowsky, Leslie “ Inside the New Right” in Fortune, Sept. 22, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Lidsky, Lawrence M. “ Safe Nuclear Power: and the Coaltion against it” in The New Republic, December 28, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Livingston, J.A. “Hedges for the Prudent Man” in The Saturday Review, March 6, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Lockman, Norman “ Big red flag on Ashcroft is Pentecostalism” in The Tennessean, Jan. 22, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Lovett, Robert A. “ Text of Lovett Statement Defending Civilian (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Limitations Upon the Military” in The New York Times, Jan. 23, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Mann, Charles C. “The Man With All The Answers” in Atlantic Monthly, January 1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Maraniss, David and Michael Weisskopf “Cashing In: the GOP revolutionaries have a sure-fire way of telling friend from foe” in The Washington Post National Weekly Edition, December 4 -10, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Marchant, Pierre “Why I Still Carry A Card” as told to Pierre Marchant by a member of the French Communist Party in Realities (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Marsh, Jeffrey “Evolution and Its Discontents” in Commentary, Nov. 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Mead, Lawrence M. “The New Welfare Debate” in Commentary, March 1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Miller, Arthur “Religion and Politics: A Question That Defies Solution” (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Morin, Richard “A Bitter Pill to the Public” in The Washington Post National Weekly Edition, April 3, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Morin, Richard and Claudia Deane “ The Balkans Conflict Becomes Personal: Public support grows for sending ground troops to remove Milosevic from power” in The Washington Post National Weekly Edition, April 12, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Nie, Norman “The Decline of Parties” (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Nuechterlein, James “George Will and American Conservatism” in Commentary, October 1983 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Quinton, Anthony “Sir Karl Popper: Knowledge as an Institution” in Encounter, Dec. 1973 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Raskin, A. H. “Unionism’s New Frontier” in The New York Times, May 22, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Raskin, A.H. “Union Leader – and Big Business Man” in The New York Times Magazine, November 15, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Reich, Robert B. “Toward a New Public Philosophy” in The Atlantic Monthly, May 1985 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Reinhardt, Uwe E. “Reaganomics, R.I.P.” in The New Republic, April 20, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Reston, James “Cats and Dogs: Mr. Nixon and the Press” in The New York Times, Oct. 30, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Robbins, William “ Jury Returns Guilty Verdict in Main Line Triple Murder” in The New York Times, January 19, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Rohatyn, Felix G. “Time for a Change” in The New York Review of Books, August 18, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Rosenbaum, David E. “20 Years Later, the Great Society Flourishes” in The New York Times (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Russell, Francis “Clinching the Case” in The New York Review of Books, March 13, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Ryerson, Andre “Capitalism and Selfishness” in Commentary, Dec. 1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Samuelson, Robert J. “The Campaign Reform Failure” in The New Republic, Sept. 5, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Schneider, William “What the Democrats Must Do” in The New Republic, March 11, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Schrag, Peter “Who Owns the Environment?” in Saturday Review, July 4, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Shanahan, Eileen “ Reformer: Urging Business Change: Interview with (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Ralph Nader” in The New York Times, Jan. 24, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Silk, Leonard “ Ailing Economy: Debt Buildup Called Cause” in The New York Times (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Strout, Richard L. “Election Process in Trouble” in The Christian Science Monitor (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Sullivan, Walter “End of Universe in ‘Black Hole’ Foreseen” in The New York Times, April 25, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Thomas, Lewis “Hubris in Science?” in Science, Vol. 200, June 30, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Toner, Robin “Poll Shows Price Bush Pays For Tough Economic Times” in The New York Times, January 10, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Uchitelle, Louis “Learning from the Big Booms” in The New York Times, June 28, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Urquhart, Brian “Reflections on the Mitchell Report” in The New York Review of Books, May 24, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Will, George “In Defense of the Welfare State: Conservatism with a Kindly Face?” in The New Republic, May 9, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Wicker, Tom “ An Unwinnable War” in The New York Times (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Wilson, Dru “ Keeping Family Heirlooms Safe” in Toronto Star, January 10, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Wilson, James Q. and John J. Dilulio, Jr. “Crackdown: Treating the symptoms of the drug problem” in The New Republic, July 10, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Wong, Edward “ Hard Times for TV Documentaries” in The New York Times, Jan. 4, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Wright, Robert “ Why Men Are Still Beasts” in The New Republic, July 11, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Articles on the C.I.A.
  - “C.I.A. Maker of Policy, or Tool?” in The New York Times, April 25 -29, 1966 (originals and photocopies) (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Articles on India
  - Articles on INDIA (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Borders, William “India’s New Governing Party Wins or Leads in 8 of 10 State Elections in The New York Times, June 15, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Nandy, Ashis “Bashiruddin Ahmed: A Scholar of Indian Democracy” in The Times of India, Sept. 14, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Traub, James “The Sorry State of India” in The New Republic, June 4, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - “Mrs. Gandhi’s Party Wins Rule in 14 States, Shattering Its Foes” in The New York Times, March 15, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - “5 Killed, Scores Hurt As India Elections Start” in The Tennessean, March 2, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Articles on Iran-Contra
  - “Text of Agreement by 5 Central American Leaders on Peace in the Region” in The New York Times, August 12, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - “The Iran- Contra Report: ‘Congress Was Not Notified’” in The New York Times, November 19, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - “No Pardon” in The New Republic, December 28, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Brinkley, Joel “ Plan for Peace, or Arms? White House Sees President’s New Offer As a Way to Win Approval on Contra Aid” (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Brinkley, Joes and Tim Weiner “ Soldiers, Secretaries, and Politicians, Now United in Bitterness in The New York Times, Jan. 19, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Buchwald, Art “ Minority, minority report on Iran-contra affair sees it a little differently” (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Cruz, Arturo, Jr. “One Hundred Years of Turpitude” in The New Republic, Nov. 16, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Draper, Theodore “An Autopsy” in New York Review of Books, Dec. 17, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Draper, Theodore “The Rise of the American Junta” in The New York Review of Books, Oct. 8, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Johnston, David “Poindexter is Found Guilty of all 5 Criminal Charges for Iran-Contra Cover-Up” in The New York Times, April 8, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Johnston, David “ Reagan Had Role in Arms Scandal, Prosecutor Says” in The New York Times, January 19, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Kinzer, Stephen “Nicaragua: The Beleaguered Revolution” in The New York Times Magazine, August 28, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Kornbluh, Peter and Byrne, Malcolm “Where the Bodies Are Buried” in The New York Times, Jan. 19, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - LeMoyne, James “Central America Backs Peace Plan” in The New York Times (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Roberts, Steven “Reagan Reports “’General’ Accord on Latin Proposal’ in The New York Times, August 6, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Safire, William “Of Meese and Men” (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Safire, William “This Bud’s for You Iran-Contra Who’s guilty of what?” (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Vinocur, John “Nicaragua: A Correspondent’s Portrait” in The New York Times, August 16, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Wicker, Tom “War Ain’t Peace Yet” (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Articles from The New Republic: Central America, Oct. 24, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Christian, Shirley “The Other Side” (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Radosh, Ronald “Darkening Nicaragua” (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Tucker, Robert W. “Their Wars, our Choices” (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Articles on Social Security
  - Berkowitz, Edward D. “The Insecurity Privatization Would Bring” in The Washington Post National Weekly Edition, January 6, 1997; Madrick, Jeff “Social Security and Its Discontents” review of Restoring Hope in America: The Social Security Solution by Sam Beard; Frightening America’s Elderly: How the Age Lobby Holds Seniors Captive by Thomas J. DiLorenzo; Will America Grow Up Before it Grows Old?: How the Coming Social Security Crisis Threatens You, Your Family, and Your Country by Peter G. Peterson; Social Security in the Twenty-First Century by Eric R. Kingson in The New York Review of Books, December 19, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Peterson, Peter G. “Social Security: The Coming Crash” in The New York Review of Books, Dec. 2, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Peterson, Peter G. “The Salvation of Social Security” in The New York Review of Books, Dec. 16, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Stevenson, Richard W. “Democratic Allies Mount Counteroffensive on Social Security” in The New York Times, June 17, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Articles by others – miscellaneous
  - “The Politics of Science: An Essay on the Relations of Power and Knowledge” (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - “Science Policy and Political Modernization” (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - “Report of Crimea Conference” Feb. 1945; “World Parley Participants” March 6, 1945; “Text of Civil Rights Bill. ..” Aug. 31, 1957; “University Presidents are Found Living in World of Ambiguities”, Dec. 24, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - “Reagan Goes Left…”; “Nixon Backed”; “Censorship Code Issued for Press” (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - “Government’s War News Policy” in The New York Times; “Implications of Sociobiology” in Science, Vol. 192, April 30, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - “Beck and Reuther, the Teamsters.. .” in The Reporter, July 5, 1949; “ Up from Crisis” in The New Republic, December 10, 1984; “The Price of a Daughter” in The Economist, September 14, 1985; “Time of suggestions on state’s busted budget”; “Hannah Arendt – Inspiration, Provocateur, Respected Foe” in The New York Times, Oct. 11, 1981; “The Labor Picture in February” (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - From the Opinion” Supreme Court of the United States, United States V. White”; Article in The Atlantic Monthly, March 1985 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Publications
  - “ Some Basic Readings in Social Security” 1936 with accompanying letter, August 4, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Report of the President’s Committee, Adminstrative Management, January 1937 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Executive Office of the President, Bureau of the Budget (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Staff Orientation Manual, February 15, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Staff Professional Roster, June 15, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Two Years of Progress Under the Federal Reports Act, March 1945 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Functions and Organization, November 1, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Official Text of Labor-Management Relations Act of 1947 (Taft- Hartley Act) and Comments Thereon (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Final Report in the article on The Causes of Industrial Peace Under Collective Bargaining, July 11, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Digest of the Hoover Commission’s Final Report to the Congress, c. 1955? (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Public Education in Tennessee, Nov. 18, 1957, Digest of a Report (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Jobs and Color: Negro Employment in Tennessee State Government, Prepared by Herman H. Long and Vivian W. Henderson, December 1962 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - The Mayors Report on the Third Year of Metropolitan Government Giving Highlights of Department, Board and Agency Reports, April, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Fourth Five Year Plan, Draft Outline, Ministry of Information and Broadcasting, Government of India (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - National Planning Association, May 1966, May 1972 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Robert A. Taft Institute of Government, Portfolios, 1966, 1967 with accompanying letter, February 23, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Science Policy in India, Occasional Paper Series, No. 1, New Delhi, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Seminar, Monthly Symposium, New Delhi, June 1967; July 1967; July 1976 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Congressman Richard Fulton’s Record in Opposition to Forced School Busing, Summer 1972 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - STPP News, May 1975 ( Dept. of Political Science, Purdue University) (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Higher Education and National Affairs, Nov. 12, 1976; Feb. 25, 1977; August 26, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Current Sweden, January 1977 (Box 8, Folder 18)